# Branden Palmer, Front-End Developer

brandenpalmer08@gmail.com | Website | Github | LinkedIn

**SUMMARY** 

Front-end developer with 2 years experience building projects in the React ecosystem. Seeking a career change into front-end development. Successful senior aviation technician with 10 years of professional experience. Adept to a career requiring a high degree of initiative.

**SKILLS** 

Proficient: React, Javascript, Storybook, TailwindCSS, CSS/SCSS, BASH/Linux, Jest, Git

**Learning:** TypeScript, Next, Firebase **Exposed:** Docker, Docker-compose

**EXPERIENCE** 

## **Open Source Contributor** - SuperProductivity

2022-04-22 - Present

https://super-productivity.com/

Advanced todo list app with 421,000+ downloads.

 Used browser tools to locate the appropriate CSS classes and added SCSS to re-center icons. Resulting change was merged, and issue was closed.

### Senior Aviation Technician - Lockheed Martin

2017-12-01 - 2020-01-01

http://lockheedmartin.com

A global security and aerospace company.

• Trained, assisted Iraqi Air Force in the maintenance of F-16 fighter aircraft.

**PROJECTS** 

#### Memespace

A social app just for memes.

2022-11-13

- Developed a standardized troubleshooting template to address a programming issue with no identifiable errors, reducing the next troubleshooting session time from two days to two hours.
- Utilized git bisect to isolate a production build failure to one commit affecting three files, providing crucial context to troubleshoot and fix the issue.
- Successfully integrated a 3rd party API to fulfill core functionality requirements, creating a module to fetch
  content, selector components, and modals for UI access, resulting in the site's access to an impressive library
  of 999 memes.
- Created a conventions document covering 10 key decisions, such as file naming and Git commits, which reduced decision fatigue and enabled faster, more meaningful development.
- Integrated Firebase BaaS for storage and user auth, added caching with React Query, custom hooks for Firebase auth state, and a loading UI. Fulfilled core social functionality while optimizing network performance.

#### **Battle Ship**

Classic board game turned digital.

2022-04-14

- Used TDD to write 35 tests covering 3 modules and 16 functions, resulting in SOLID game logic code that was easier to refactor and understand.
- Applied Martin Fowler's Refactoring principles, including the Two Hats and Incremental Refactoring principles, to systematically refactor a disorganized codebase. As a result, a new feature, the random ship placement button, was implemented in just 15 minutes.
- Implemented a style system using SCSS and the BEM method, with separate files for each screen, resulting in a coherent, easy-to-use, high-quality style system.
- Developed a rendering system by creating a render module in Vanilla JS that supported four screens with 18 components. Resulting in a manageable rendering API that effectively hid implementation details.

**EDUCATION** 

## Community College of the Air Force

2012 - 2014

AAS - Aviation Maintenance Technology